Shady Saleh

Orange, CA 92868 | Phone: (714)203-4290 | Email: shadysaleh01@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://github.com/shadysaleh01/ | Portfolio:

https://shadysaleh01.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Bachelor's in Computer Science and Full Stack Certificate from the University of California, Los Angeles with a lifelong commitment to learning and growing in the technical field. Pursuing a position as a Full Stack developer to apply front-end and back-end knowledge and experience. Dedicated to combining creativity and problem solving skills to develop clean code for user-friendly applications and websites. Passionate about projects in UI and UX web design and the optimization of website functionality. Highly experienced in many programming frameworks, debugging, and Dom manipulation.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, AJAX, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL,

MongoDB, Express servers, Handlebars, Error Handling & ReactJS.

Applications: Brackets, Visual Studio Code, Notepad++, Git Bash, Adobe XD, Node.js, Sequelize, Testing,

Heroku, PWAs, MERN

Projects

Project Name: Barber App

GitHub: https://bit.ly/36Gzl4p | Live Link: https://bit.ly/36H6gx9

- **Summary:** This is a barber app with a similar concept to Uber, which allows users to request barbers to the comfort of their own home or hotel room. Users can view barber profiles, check out prices and reviews, view menus of barber services, request barbers, pay, and review their experience through the app.
- **Responsibilities:** Worked on the complete front end including: creating a React app with its components and 19 pages, and dynamic navigation bars.
- Tools / Languages: React, js, JSX, CSS, JavaScript, API, Axios, React google map, Font Awesome.

Project Name: Al Face & Mouth Detection

GitHub: https://bit.ly/36GzCEt | Live Link: https://bit.ly/36GzCEt | Live Link: https://bit.ly/3tofqRE

- **Summary:** Developed a Face Detection website to recognize user facial expressions. Depending on how the user will react, a message is displayed with an appropriate response to the user's current facial expression. Created a mouth detection feature that knows when the user is speaking or not and will mute and unmute accordingly.
- Responsibilities: Front End: Dynamic Navigation Bar, Logo, completely worked on Face Detection
 Expression, About Us and Developer Sections, also the Footer and all dynamic buttons. Back End:
 Gained access to webcam and linked facial recognition API to determine the user's expression. When
 the facial recognition detects an emotion, it is displayed in the demographic section to the left of the
 camera. Connected Joke Rendering API to the Feeling section to display a joke based on the user's
 current expression.
- Tools / Languages: HTML, CSS, Foundation, JavaScript, jQuery, Face API, Ajax, Font Awesome.

Project Name: Learn Squad

Github: https://bit.ly/3oLavXi | Live Link: https://bit.ly/3cDfgQl

- **Summary**: This application is a clan based trivia game in which users must create an account, choose a team, answer questions based on one of the 6 categories, and are limited by time. Top scorers will appear on the Top 10 page.
- **Responsibilities**: Back-end: database, server, routes, mySQL, APIs. Front-end: AJAX, Login/Sign up credentials, and Top 10 pages.

• <u>Tools / Languages:</u> HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery,Git, Node.js, Heroku, framework and Visual Studio Code.

Project Name: Eat-Da-Burger!

GitHub: https://bit.ly/3jdnW10 | Live Link: https://bit.ly/2YGMTIT

• <u>Summary:</u> A restaurant app that lets users input burgers they'd like to eat. The app will display the burger on the waiting list to be eaten with an Eat Me! Button next to it. By clicking it, the burger will move to the Eaten list with a Remove Button next to it. This app will store every burger in a database, whether eaten or not.

Tools / Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, node.js, Heroku, and Visual Studio Code.

Experience

CEO 08/2017-Current Orange County, CA

- Created my own ecommerce company which utilizes sales channels such as Amazon, Walmart & eBay Marketplaces to be sold nationally and internationally.
- Design my own products to be manufactured and sold on various sales platforms (FBA).
- Licensed to sell global brands such as TOMS and Puma (drop-shipping).
- Manage, label, ship and handle products in my company warehouse.

1st Camera Assistant THE SOUNDFIELD POST

06/2017-03/2020

West Hollywood, CA

- Ensure equipment is up to par with studio standards; utilize problem solving skills to handle any problems that come up during production shoots.
- Communicated and collaborated with cinematographer, sound mixer and coordinators and other team members for the shoot list.
- Downloaded footage and maintained camera gear and slate scenes to Director's discretion.

Event Coordinator Aswani Media

02/2011-03/2017

Mohandessin, Cairo

- Participated in the development of event planning including details such as location, time, and budget.
- Led a diverse team of up to 150 staff from different departments of the event which included parking, security, cleaning, and greeters.
- Coordinated with various food, snacks, and beverage vendors such as McDonald's, KFC, Pepsi and Cook Door to set up food trucks at the events, and made sure each of them followed food and safety guideline requirements.
- Designed promotional items for staff to wear during events and distribute to event-goers.
- Enforced staff dress code rules.

Key Accomplishments:

- Responsible for creating new sales opportunities in order to increase event profits.
- Trusted with the ability to make essential decisions for the company without consulting the owner.
- Became the Director of Operations and was in charge of leading all the supervisors in the company.
- Recognized and awarded for outstanding leadership skills by the owner of the company.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate:

12/2020

University of California, Los Angeles,

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

B.S. in Computer Science:

05/2016

New Cairo Academy, Cairo, Egypt